((LIST OF CHATROOMS))

((SHAREDTALK **BEST I'VE COME ACROSS LATELY**))

Sharedtalk has two types of chatting options. You can either do voice
chat or text chat. I would recommend you if you're a beginner to use
text chat until you become more comfortable with the language. The
worst thing you want to happen is being overwhelmed and discouraged
at an early stage of your studies.

http://www.SharedTalk.com

((YAHOO CHAT))

I haven't used Yahoo chat as much as I used to a long time ago, but
when I did it was very good. They have many different rooms for various
languages such as Chinese, Hindi, Japanese, Spanish etc. Create yourself
a username and try it out. Beware of spam bots and theannoying questions
like ''ASL'' 'Age Sex Location' It gets a little anoying after a while,
but you'll still be able to find someone nice to chat with.

http://im.about.com/od/yahoomessenge1/a/yahoo-chat.htm

((PALTALK))

Paltalk is good and it seems to be growing more and more these days.
My only problem with Paltalk is the lack of support for foreign texts.
Maybe they've updated this problem, but then I used it before, I 
couldn't even type in Chinese. This was very dissapointing. However,
it is very good for getting good practice.

http://www.paltalk.com/

((LIVEMOCHA))

I've only tried LiveMocha once, but with little success. I wanted to 
try again, but didn't have the time.

http://livemocha.com/

((SKYPE))

Very useful tool for practicing language. It isn't a chatroom perse,
however you can make freinds and have conference calls. When you use
other chatting sites and make friends with someone, make sure to ask
for their skype because this will be a great way to stay in contact 
for consistent practice.

http://www.skype.com/en/

((Lang-8 **For getting texts corrected**))

Lang-8 isn't really a chatroom. This website is mainly used for getting
sentences/paragraphs corrected by native speakers. You should definitely
check it out.

http://lang-8.com/


