Q:Where did you learn Spain?
P:Donde aprendiste Español?
A:I learned Spanish in my home
R.Aprendí Español en mi casa 
-------------------------------------
Q:Where in the country have you been?
P:En qué parte del país has estado?
A:When I went to Spain, I was in Barcelona
R.Cuando me fuí a España, estube en Barcelona 
----------------------------------------------
Q:Where in Spain will you go?
P:A que lugar de España vas a ir?
A:If I go to Spain, perhaps I will go to Barcelona
R:Si me voy a España, tal vez voy a ir a Barcelona. 
----------------------------------------------------
Q:Where is your hometown?
P:Donde es tu ciudad natal?
A:My hometown is Akron, Ohio
R:Mi ciudad natal es Akron,Ohio 
----------------------------------------------------
Q:Where do you want to go?
P:Donde quieres ir?
A:I want to go to Barcelona
R:Yo quiero ir a Barcelona
----------------------------------
Q:Why are you interested in Spanish?
P:Por qué te interesa el Español?
A:I’m interested in Spanish because I think it’s an interesting language
R:Estoy interesado en el Español porque creo que es un idioma interesante. 
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
((KEYWORDS))

TO MAKE (MAKE SOMETHING HAPPEN)，A REALIZAR
ONCE IN A WHILE, DE VEZ EN CUANDO
ALWAYS, SIEMPRE
ESPECIALLY SOBRE TODO –ESPECIALMENTE SI
LIKE THIS, COMO ESTO
LIKE THAT, COMO AQUELLO
MUST, DEBE
SIMPLY, SIMPLE
YET, TODAVIA 
FEEL, SENTIR
HOPE THAT, ESPERO QUE
--------------------------------------------------------------

((EXTRA MATERIAL FOR INCORPORATING WITH ABOVE MATERIAL))

I don't know=NO LO  SÉ
I don't understand=NO LO ENTIENDO
Please repeat it= POR FAVOR REPITALO
Please speak slowly= POR FAVOR, HABLE DESPACIO
Please write it down=POR FAVOR ESCRIBALO
Please explain it=POR FAVOR, EXPLIQUELO
How do you say (…)=¿CÓMO SE DICE (...)
What is the meaning of (…)= ¿CUÁL ES EL SIGNIFICADO DE (...)
How do you say ( ) in Spanish?=COMO DIRIA  (…….) EN ESPAÑOL?

INCORPORATING DIFFICULTIES WITH KEY WORDS:
DIFICULTADES QUE INCORPORA CON PALABRAS CLAVE:

I don't know, (but) (I'm sure) I will know after you explain it
YO NO SÉ, (PERO) (ESTOY SEGURO) LO SABRÉ DESPUÉS DE QUE LO EXPLIQUE

I don't understand, (but) after you explain it, (perhaps) I will understand
NO LO ENTIENDO, (PERO) DESPUÉS DE EXPLICARLO, (QUIZAS) VOY A ENTENDER

I don't understand (therefore) please write it down (in order) for me to understand
NO LO ENTIENDO (POR LO TANTO), POR FAVOR ANÓTELO (DE MANERA) QUE YO ENTIENDA

I (think) you're speaking (too) fast. Could you speak more slowly (for me?)
YO (CREO) QUE ESTÁ HABLANDO (DEMASIADO) RÁPIDO. ¿PODRÍA HABLAR MÁS DESPACIO 
(PARA MÍ?)
               
