Q: How do you write (......)
P: COMO SE ESCRIBRE (…)
A: You can write it like this
R. PUEDES ESCRIBIRLO DE ESTA FORMA
------------------------------------------
Q: How are you learning Spanish? 
P: COMO ESTAS APRENDIENDO ESPAÑOL
A: I’m learning Spanish by using textbooks and practicing with native speakers 
R:ESTOY APRENDIENDO ESPAÑOL UTILIZANDO LIBROS DE TEXTO Y PRACTICANDO CON HABLANTES 
NATIVOS.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Q:Which countries have you been to?
P:EN QUE PAISES HAS ESTADO?
A:I’ve been to Taiwan and Japan
R: HE ESTADO EN TAIWAN Y EN JAPON
------------------------------------------
Q:Which books are you using to learn Spanish?
P:QUE LIBROS ESTAS USANDO PARA 
A:I’m using a textbook called ‘’Teach Yourself’’  
R:ESTOY UTILIZANDO EL LIBRO DE TEXTO LLAMADO “APRENDA USTED MISMO”
--------------------------------------------------------------------                                                                                    APRENDER ESPAÑOL ?
Q:Which city do you live in? 
P:EN QUE CIUDAD VIVE USTED?
A:I live in Columbus, Ohio   
R:YO VIVO EN COLUMBUS, OHIO
-------------------------------
Q:Which language do you enjoy learning the most?   
P:EN QUE IDIOMA TE GUSTA APRENDER MAS? 
A:Actually, I enjoy learning Asian languages the most. 
R:ACTUALMENTE, ME GUSTA mucho MAS APRENDER IDIOMAS ASIATICOS
-----------------------------------------------------------------
((KEYWORDS))

FOR ME PARA MI
MORE MAS
THE XXX... EL...
THE BETTER, EL MEJOR
EASIEST, MAS FACIL
MOST DIFFICULT (SUPERLATIVE),  MAS DIFICIL
TOO (EXCESSIVE), MUY
ALSO, ADEMAS, TAMBIEN
IN COMPARISON TO, EN COMPARACION CON
CERTAINLY,  CIERTAMENTE
IN MY OPINION, EN MI OPINION 
TO ME, A MI
IN MY POINT OF VIEW,  EN MI PUNTO DE VISTA
---------------------------------------------------------------

((EXTRA MATERIAL FOR INCORPORATING WITH ABOVE MATERIAL))

I don't know=NO LO  SÉ
I don't understand=NO LO ENTIENDO
Please repeat it= POR FAVOR REPITALO
Please speak slowly= POR FAVOR, HABLE DESPACIO
Please write it down=POR FAVOR ESCRIBALO
Please explain it=POR FAVOR, EXPLIQUELO
How do you say (…)=¿CÓMO SE DICE (...)
What is the meaning of (…)= ¿CUÁL ES EL SIGNIFICADO DE (...)
How do you say ( ) in Spanish?=COMO DIRIA  (…….) EN ESPAÑOL?

INCORPORATING DIFFICULTIES WITH KEY WORDS:
DIFICULTADES QUE INCORPORA CON PALABRAS CLAVE:

I don't know, (but) (I'm sure) I will know after you explain it
YO NO SÉ, (PERO) (ESTOY SEGURO) LO SABRÉ DESPUÉS DE QUE LO EXPLIQUE

I don't understand, (but) after you explain it, (perhaps) I will understand
NO LO ENTIENDO, (PERO) DESPUÉS DE EXPLICARLO, (QUIZAS) VOY A ENTENDER

I don't understand (therefore) please write it down (in order) for me to understand
NO LO ENTIENDO (POR LO TANTO), POR FAVOR ANÓTELO (DE MANERA) QUE YO ENTIENDA

I (think) you're speaking (too) fast. Could you speak more slowly (for me?)
YO (CREO) QUE ESTÁ HABLANDO (DEMASIADO) RÁPIDO. ¿PODRÍA HABLAR MÁS DESPACIO 
(PARA MÍ?)
               