Q:Which languages are you learning? 
P:QUE IDIOMAS ESTAS APRENDIENDO?
A:Right now, I’m learning Chinese, Japanese and Korean etc. 
R:EN ESTE MOMENTO, ESTOY APRENDIENDO CHINO, JAPONES Y KOREANO
------------------------------------------------------------------
Q: What kind of food do you like? 
P: QUE TIPO DE COMIDA TE GUSTA?
A: I like to eat very spicy food. 
R. ME GUSTA COMER LA COMIDA MUY PICANTE
----------------------------------------
Q: What kind of audio are you using for German? 
P: QUE TIPO DE AUDIO ESTAS UTILIZANDO PARA ALEMAN?
A: I use the audio that comes with Teach Yourself. I also like to use a program 
called ‘’Pimsleur’’ 
R. YO ESTUDIO EL AUDIO QUE VIENE CON “APRENDA USTED MISMO”. TAMBIEN ME GUSTA USAR 
UN PROGRAMA LLAMADO  “PIMSLEUR”
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Q: Have you ever been to Spain? 
P. HAS ESTADO ALGUNA VEZ EN ESPAÑA?
A: I've never been to Spain before, (but) (I'm sure) one day I will get the 
opportunity to go there. 
R. NUNCA HE ESTADO ES ESPAÑA ANTES, PERO ESTOY SEGURO UN DIA VOY A TENER LA 
OPORTUNIDAD DE IR ALLA.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Q: Do you think Spanish is difficult? P: CREES QUE  EL ESPAÑOL ES DIFICIL?
A: Since English is my native tongue, I think Spanish is very difficult. 
However, I must work hard in order to learn it. R. DADO QUE EL INGLES ES MI 
LENGUA MATERNA, YO PIESO QUE EL ESPAÑOL ES MUY DIFICIL. SIN EMBARGO, TENGO QUE 
TRABAJAR DURO PARA PODER APRENDERLO.
----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Q:WHO'S TEACHING YOU THE LANGUAGE
¿QUIÉN TE ENSEÑANZA EL IDIOMA
A: I'm learning the language on my own (now), (but),(although) I'm learning on my
own, I don't (think) it's a difficult task. (As long as) I (continue) to work hard,
I will be successful.
ESTOY APRENDIENDO EL IDIOMA POR MI CUENTA (AHORA), (PERO), (AUNQUE) ESTOY 
APRENDIENDO POR MI PROPIA CUENTA, NO (CREO) QUE SEA UNA TAREA DIFÍCIL.(MIENTRAS) 
YO (CONTINUE) TRABAJANDO DURO, VOY A TENER ÉXITO.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
¿QUÉ IDIOMAS ESTÁS APRENDIENDO?
WHICH LANGUAGES ARE YOU LEARNING?

(AHORA) ESTOY APRENDIENDO ESPAÑOL, ALEMÁN, CHINO (Y) JAPONES, (PERO) YO VOY  
(PROBABLEMENTE) EMPEZAR A APRENDER  (OTROS) IDIOMAS (PORQUE) YO (CREO) QUE EL 
APRENDER (VARIOS) IDIOMAS AL MISMO TIEMPO ES MUY ENRIQUECEDOR. (AUNQUE) ESO 
(PUEDE) SER DIFÍCIL PARA UNA PERSONA, (AL MENOS) EL PROCESO DE APRENDIZAJE SERÁ 
DIVERTIDO.

(Now) I'm learning Spanish, German, Chinese (and) Japanese, (but) I will 
(probably) start learning (other) Languages (because) I (believe) that learning 
(many) languages at the same time is very enriching. (Although) it (may) be 
difficult for an individual, (at least) the learning process will be fun.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
((KEYWORDS))

SOON,  PRONTO
AS A MATTER OF FACT,  COMO DE HECHO
IN FACT, DE HECHO, EN  REALIDAD
HONESTLY, HONESTAMENTE
ACTUALLY，ACTUALMENTE
ALREADY,  YA
HEARD THAT, ESCUCHO QUE
FOR SURE, SIN DUDA
HAD BETTER (I'D BETTER), TENIAN MEJORES (MEJOR QUE ME )
ABOUT, ALREDEDOR
EVEN. INCLUSO
--------------------------------------------------------------------

((EXTRA MATERIAL FOR INCORPORATING WITH ABOVE MATERIAL))

I don't know=NO LO  SÉ
I don't understand=NO LO ENTIENDO
Please repeat it= POR FAVOR REPITALO
Please speak slowly= POR FAVOR, HABLE DESPACIO
Please write it down=POR FAVOR ESCRIBALO
Please explain it=POR FAVOR, EXPLIQUELO
How do you say (…)=¿CÓMO SE DICE (...)
What is the meaning of (…)= ¿CUÁL ES EL SIGNIFICADO DE (...)
How do you say ( ) in Spanish?=COMO DIRIA  (…….) EN ESPAÑOL?

INCORPORATING DIFFICULTIES WITH KEY WORDS:
DIFICULTADES QUE INCORPORA CON PALABRAS CLAVE:

I don't know, (but) (I'm sure) I will know after you explain it
YO NO SÉ, (PERO) (ESTOY SEGURO) LO SABRÉ DESPUÉS DE QUE LO EXPLIQUE

I don't understand, (but) after you explain it, (perhaps) I will understand
NO LO ENTIENDO, (PERO) DESPUÉS DE EXPLICARLO, (QUIZAS) VOY A ENTENDER

I don't understand (therefore) please write it down (in order) for me to understand
NO LO ENTIENDO (POR LO TANTO), POR FAVOR ANÓTELO (DE MANERA) QUE YO ENTIENDA

I (think) you're speaking (too) fast. Could you speak more slowly (for me?)
YO (CREO) QUE ESTÁ HABLANDO (DEMASIADO) RÁPIDO. ¿PODRÍA HABLAR MÁS DESPACIO 
(PARA MÍ?)
               

