Q: What is today's date?
P: Qué fecha es hoy?
A: Today is March, 25th 2011-03-25
R: Hoy es 25 de Marzo de 2011
--------------------------------------------
Q: What are your hobbies?
P: Cuales son tus pasatiempos favoritos?
A: I like to study languages, go fishing and play video game
R: Me gusta estudiar idiomas, ir de pesca y jugar videojuegos.
--------------------------------------------------------------
Q:When did you start learning Spanish?
P:Cuando comenzaste a aprender Español ?
A:I started learning Spanish two months ago
R: Comencé a aprender Español hace 
--------------------------------------------------------------                                                                                      dos meses.
Q:When did you go to Spain?
P:Cuando fuiste a España?
A:I have never been to Spain, but if I go, I want to go to Barcelona
R: Nunca he estado en España, pero si me voy, quiero ir a Barcelona
--------------------------------------------------------------------
Q:When will you go to Spain?
P:Cuando vas a ir a España?
A:I will go to Spain after I graduate
R.Voy a ir a España despues de graduarme
---------------------------------------------
Q:Where are you from?
P:De donde eres?
A:I am from the United States
R.Yo soy de Estados Unidos de Norteamérica
---------------------------------------------
((KEYWORDS))

THAN QUE
AS LONG AS, SIEMPRE Y CUANDO
CONTINUE, CONTINÚA
STILL, TODAVÍA
PROBABLY, PROBABLEMENTE
MAYBE, TAL VEZ
USUALLY, POR LO GENERAL - USUALMENTE
SOMETIMES, A VECES
OK,ESTÁ BIEN
I SEE,YA VEO
--------------------------------------------------------------

((EXTRA MATERIAL FOR INCORPORATING WITH ABOVE MATERIAL))

I don't know=NO LO  SÉ
I don't understand=NO LO ENTIENDO
Please repeat it= POR FAVOR REPITALO
Please speak slowly= POR FAVOR, HABLE DESPACIO
Please write it down=POR FAVOR ESCRIBALO
Please explain it=POR FAVOR, EXPLIQUELO
How do you say (…)=¿CÓMO SE DICE (...)
What is the meaning of (…)= ¿CUÁL ES EL SIGNIFICADO DE (...)
How do you say ( ) in Spanish?=COMO DIRIA  (…….) EN ESPAÑOL?

INCORPORATING DIFFICULTIES WITH KEY WORDS:
DIFICULTADES QUE INCORPORA CON PALABRAS CLAVE:

I don't know, (but) (I'm sure) I will know after you explain it
YO NO SÉ, (PERO) (ESTOY SEGURO) LO SABRÉ DESPUÉS DE QUE LO EXPLIQUE

I don't understand, (but) after you explain it, (perhaps) I will understand
NO LO ENTIENDO, (PERO) DESPUÉS DE EXPLICARLO, (QUIZAS) VOY A ENTENDER

I don't understand (therefore) please write it down (in order) for me to understand
NO LO ENTIENDO (POR LO TANTO), POR FAVOR ANÓTELO (DE MANERA) QUE YO ENTIENDA

I (think) you're speaking (too) fast. Could you speak more slowly (for me?)
YO (CREO) QUE ESTÁ HABLANDO (DEMASIADO) RÁPIDO. ¿PODRÍA HABLAR MÁS DESPACIO 
(PARA MÍ?)
               
