Q: Who's teaching you Spanish?
A: I’m self-taught/ I teach myself
P: Quién está enseñándote Español?
R: Yo soy autodidacta / ( answer in Spanish is the same, like a sinonimus) 
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Q: Who taught you Spanish?
A: I taught myself
P: Quién te enseñó Español?
R: Aprendí yo mismo
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Q: Who did you learn Spanish from?
A: I studied it independently
P: De quien aprendiste Español?
R: Lo estudié de forma independiente
----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Q: Who is your teacher?
A: I don’t have a teacher/ My teacher is Moses 
P: Quién es tu profesor?
R: Yo no tengo profesor/ Mi profesor
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Q: What is your name? 
A: My name is ( )
P: Cuál es tu nombre?
R: Mi nombre es (…)
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Q: What's your reason for learning Spanish?
A: I want to learn Spanish because I want to go to Spain one day                                                                                             Español?
P:Cual es tu razón para aprender español 
R: Quiero aprender español porque quiero ir a España algún día     
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 
                                            
((KEYWORDS))       

ALTHOUGH SI BIEN
BUT PERO,
EVEN IF, INCLUSO SI
IF  SI,
WHEN (WHEN SOMETHING OCCURS),  CUANDO (CUANDO ALGO OCURRE), 
AND, Y
NOW, AHORA
OTHER, OTRO
TOLD ME, ME DIJO 

((EXTRA MATERIAL FOR INCORPORATING WITH ABOVE MATERIAL))

I don't know=NO LO  SÉ
I don't understand=NO LO ENTIENDO
Please repeat it= POR FAVOR REPITALO
Please speak slowly= POR FAVOR, HABLE DESPACIO
Please write it down=POR FAVOR ESCRIBALO
Please explain it=POR FAVOR, EXPLIQUELO
How do you say (…)=¿CÓMO SE DICE (...)
What is the meaning of (…)= ¿CUÁL ES EL SIGNIFICADO DE (...)
How do you say ( ) in Spanish?=COMO DIRIA  (…….) EN ESPAÑOL?

INCORPORATING DIFFICULTIES WITH KEY WORDS:
DIFICULTADES QUE INCORPORA CON PALABRAS CLAVE:

I don't know, (but) (I'm sure) I will know after you explain it
YO NO SÉ, (PERO) (ESTOY SEGURO) LO SABRÉ DESPUÉS DE QUE LO EXPLIQUE

I don't understand, (but) after you explain it, (perhaps) I will understand
NO LO ENTIENDO, (PERO) DESPUÉS DE EXPLICARLO, (QUIZAS) VOY A ENTENDER

I don't understand (therefore) please write it down (in order) for me to understand
NO LO ENTIENDO (POR LO TANTO), POR FAVOR ANÓTELO (DE MANERA) QUE YO ENTIENDA

I (think) you're speaking (too) fast. Could you speak more slowly (for me?)
YO (CREO) QUE ESTÁ HABLANDO (DEMASIADO) RÁPIDO. ¿PODRÍA HABLAR MÁS DESPACIO 
(PARA MÍ?)
                                                                                                            es Moises﻿Q: What is your job? 
P: Cuál es tu Trabajo?
A: I’m a student
R: Soy Estudiante
------------------------------
Q: What do you do?
P: A qué te dedicas?
A: I study at the university. I’m a teacher
R: Yo estudio en la universidad. Soy Profesor.
-----------------------------------------------
Q: What is your age/How old are you?
P: Cuál es tu edad? / Cuántos años tienes?
A: I’m (  ) years old.
R: Yo tengo (…) años de edad          
------------------------------------------------
Q: What do you do in your spare time?
P: Qué haces en tu tiempo libre?
A: When I have time, I like to go fishing and play video games with my friends.
R: Cuando tengo tiempo, me gusta ir a pescar y jugar videojuegos con mis amigos.
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Q: What does this mean?
P: Qué significa esto?
A: This means ‘’Book’’
R: Esto significa “Libro”         
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Q: What time is it?
P: Qué hora es?
A: It is already 5:00 PM
R: Son ya las 5:00pm
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------
((KEYWORDS))

MOREOVER, POR OTRA PARTE
WHENEVER, CADA VEZ 
OR, O
ALSO, TAMBIÉN -ADEMAS
BECAUSE, PORQUE
AFTER DESPUÉS
BEFORE ANTES
TO THINK, A PENSAR
VERY, MUY
IS THAT SO? , ¿ES ASÍ?
-----------------------------------------------------------

((EXTRA MATERIAL FOR INCORPORATING WITH ABOVE MATERIAL))

I don't know=NO LO  SÉ
I don't understand=NO LO ENTIENDO
Please repeat it= POR FAVOR REPITALO
Please speak slowly= POR FAVOR, HABLE DESPACIO
Please write it down=POR FAVOR ESCRIBALO
Please explain it=POR FAVOR, EXPLIQUELO
How do you say (…)=¿CÓMO SE DICE (...)
What is the meaning of (…)= ¿CUÁL ES EL SIGNIFICADO DE (...)
How do you say ( ) in Spanish?=COMO DIRIA  (…….) EN ESPAÑOL?

INCORPORATING DIFFICULTIES WITH KEY WORDS:
DIFICULTADES QUE INCORPORA CON PALABRAS CLAVE:

I don't know, (but) (I'm sure) I will know after you explain it
YO NO SÉ, (PERO) (ESTOY SEGURO) LO SABRÉ DESPUÉS DE QUE LO EXPLIQUE

I don't understand, (but) after you explain it, (perhaps) I will understand
NO LO ENTIENDO, (PERO) DESPUÉS DE EXPLICARLO, (QUIZAS) VOY A ENTENDER

I don't understand (therefore) please write it down (in order) for me to understand
NO LO ENTIENDO (POR LO TANTO), POR FAVOR ANÓTELO (DE MANERA) QUE YO ENTIENDA

I (think) you're speaking (too) fast. Could you speak more slowly (for me?)
YO (CREO) QUE ESTÁ HABLANDO (DEMASIADO) RÁPIDO. ¿PODRÍA HABLAR MÁS DESPACIO 
(PARA MÍ?)
               
﻿Q: What is today's date?
P: Qué fecha es hoy?
A: Today is March, 25th 2011-03-25
R: Hoy es 25 de Marzo de 2011
--------------------------------------------
Q: What are your hobbies?
P: Cuales son tus pasatiempos favoritos?
A: I like to study languages, go fishing and play video game
R: Me gusta estudiar idiomas, ir de pesca y jugar videojuegos.
--------------------------------------------------------------
Q:When did you start learning Spanish?
P:Cuando comenzaste a aprender Español ?
A:I started learning Spanish two months ago
R: Comencé a aprender Español hace 
--------------------------------------------------------------                                                                                      dos meses.
Q:When did you go to Spain?
P:Cuando fuiste a España?
A:I have never been to Spain, but if I go, I want to go to Barcelona
R: Nunca he estado en España, pero si me voy, quiero ir a Barcelona
--------------------------------------------------------------------
Q:When will you go to Spain?
P:Cuando vas a ir a España?
A:I will go to Spain after I graduate
R.Voy a ir a España despues de graduarme
---------------------------------------------
Q:Where are you from?
P:De donde eres?
A:I am from the United States
R.Yo soy de Estados Unidos de Norteamérica
---------------------------------------------
((KEYWORDS))

THAN QUE
AS LONG AS, SIEMPRE Y CUANDO
CONTINUE, CONTINÚA
STILL, TODAVÍA
PROBABLY, PROBABLEMENTE
MAYBE, TAL VEZ
USUALLY, POR LO GENERAL - USUALMENTE
SOMETIMES, A VECES
OK,ESTÁ BIEN
I SEE,YA VEO
--------------------------------------------------------------

((EXTRA MATERIAL FOR INCORPORATING WITH ABOVE MATERIAL))

I don't know=NO LO  SÉ
I don't understand=NO LO ENTIENDO
Please repeat it= POR FAVOR REPITALO
Please speak slowly= POR FAVOR, HABLE DESPACIO
Please write it down=POR FAVOR ESCRIBALO
Please explain it=POR FAVOR, EXPLIQUELO
How do you say (…)=¿CÓMO SE DICE (...)
What is the meaning of (…)= ¿CUÁL ES EL SIGNIFICADO DE (...)
How do you say ( ) in Spanish?=COMO DIRIA  (…….) EN ESPAÑOL?

INCORPORATING DIFFICULTIES WITH KEY WORDS:
DIFICULTADES QUE INCORPORA CON PALABRAS CLAVE:

I don't know, (but) (I'm sure) I will know after you explain it
YO NO SÉ, (PERO) (ESTOY SEGURO) LO SABRÉ DESPUÉS DE QUE LO EXPLIQUE

I don't understand, (but) after you explain it, (perhaps) I will understand
NO LO ENTIENDO, (PERO) DESPUÉS DE EXPLICARLO, (QUIZAS) VOY A ENTENDER

I don't understand (therefore) please write it down (in order) for me to understand
NO LO ENTIENDO (POR LO TANTO), POR FAVOR ANÓTELO (DE MANERA) QUE YO ENTIENDA

I (think) you're speaking (too) fast. Could you speak more slowly (for me?)
YO (CREO) QUE ESTÁ HABLANDO (DEMASIADO) RÁPIDO. ¿PODRÍA HABLAR MÁS DESPACIO 
(PARA MÍ?)
               
﻿Q:Where did you learn Spain?
P:Donde aprendiste Español?
A:I learned Spanish in my home
R.Aprendí Español en mi casa 
-------------------------------------
Q:Where in the country have you been?
P:En qué parte del país has estado?
A:When I went to Spain, I was in Barcelona
R.Cuando me fuí a España, estube en Barcelona 
----------------------------------------------
Q:Where in Spain will you go?
P:A que lugar de España vas a ir?
A:If I go to Spain, perhaps I will go to Barcelona
R:Si me voy a España, tal vez voy a ir a Barcelona. 
----------------------------------------------------
Q:Where is your hometown?
P:Donde es tu ciudad natal?
A:My hometown is Akron, Ohio
R:Mi ciudad natal es Akron,Ohio 
----------------------------------------------------
Q:Where do you want to go?
P:Donde quieres ir?
A:I want to go to Barcelona
R:Yo quiero ir a Barcelona
----------------------------------
Q:Why are you interested in Spanish?
P:Por qué te interesa el Español?
A:I’m interested in Spanish because I think it’s an interesting language
R:Estoy interesado en el Español porque creo que es un idioma interesante. 
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
((KEYWORDS))

TO MAKE (MAKE SOMETHING HAPPEN)，A REALIZAR
ONCE IN A WHILE, DE VEZ EN CUANDO
ALWAYS, SIEMPRE
ESPECIALLY SOBRE TODO –ESPECIALMENTE SI
LIKE THIS, COMO ESTO
LIKE THAT, COMO AQUELLO
MUST, DEBE
SIMPLY, SIMPLE
YET, TODAVIA 
FEEL, SENTIR
HOPE THAT, ESPERO QUE
--------------------------------------------------------------

((EXTRA MATERIAL FOR INCORPORATING WITH ABOVE MATERIAL))

I don't know=NO LO  SÉ
I don't understand=NO LO ENTIENDO
Please repeat it= POR FAVOR REPITALO
Please speak slowly= POR FAVOR, HABLE DESPACIO
Please write it down=POR FAVOR ESCRIBALO
Please explain it=POR FAVOR, EXPLIQUELO
How do you say (…)=¿CÓMO SE DICE (...)
What is the meaning of (…)= ¿CUÁL ES EL SIGNIFICADO DE (...)
How do you say ( ) in Spanish?=COMO DIRIA  (…….) EN ESPAÑOL?

INCORPORATING DIFFICULTIES WITH KEY WORDS:
DIFICULTADES QUE INCORPORA CON PALABRAS CLAVE:

I don't know, (but) (I'm sure) I will know after you explain it
YO NO SÉ, (PERO) (ESTOY SEGURO) LO SABRÉ DESPUÉS DE QUE LO EXPLIQUE

I don't understand, (but) after you explain it, (perhaps) I will understand
NO LO ENTIENDO, (PERO) DESPUÉS DE EXPLICARLO, (QUIZAS) VOY A ENTENDER

I don't understand (therefore) please write it down (in order) for me to understand
NO LO ENTIENDO (POR LO TANTO), POR FAVOR ANÓTELO (DE MANERA) QUE YO ENTIENDA

I (think) you're speaking (too) fast. Could you speak more slowly (for me?)
YO (CREO) QUE ESTÁ HABLANDO (DEMASIADO) RÁPIDO. ¿PODRÍA HABLAR MÁS DESPACIO 
(PARA MÍ?)
               
﻿Q: Why did you choose to learn Spanish?
P : Por qué escogiste aprender Español?
A: I decided to learn Spanish because I plan to go to Spain one day
R. Decidí aprender español porque tengo planeado ir a España algún día.
-------------------------------------------------------------------------
Q: Why do you think Spanish is interesting?
P:Por qué piensas que el Español es interesante?
A: I think Spanish is interesting because I like the way it’s spoken
R. Pienso que el español es interesante porque me gusta la forma en que se habla.
----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Q: How did you learn Spanish?
P:Cómo aprendiste Español?
A: I learned Spanish by using textbooks and going to chat rooms in order to find 
Spanish people for practice.
R. Aprendí Español mediante el uso de libros de texto y entrado en las salas de 
conversación con el fin de encontrar hispanohablantes para practicar.
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Q: How long have you been learning Spanish for?
P: Por cuanto tiempo has estado aprendiendo español?
A: I’ve been learning Spanish for two months already
R. He estado aprendiendo español desde hace dos meses ya.
--------------------------------------------------------------
Q: How much time do you spend studying Spanish? 
P: Cuanto tiempo dedicas a estudiar Español?
A: Normally, I spend at least 3 hours studying Spanish.
R. Normalmente, dedico al menos 3 horas estudiando Español.
-----------------------------------------------------------------
Q: How do you say (......)
P. Como se dice (…..)
A: It’s said this way…
R. Se dice de esta manera ……
--------------------------------
((KEYWORDS))

JUST, SOLO 
JUST A MINUTE AGO, HACE UN MINUTO
FOR EXAMPLE, POR EJEMPLO
（ AS SOON AS）, (APENAS
BELIEVE, CREO
WITH, CON
AT LEAST AL MENOS
MORE AND MORE，MAS Y MAS
MOST INTERESTING OF ALL  LO MAS INTERESANTE DE TODO
SEEMS PARECE
I'M SURE THAT, ESTOY SEGURO QUE
IN ORDER TO  CON EL FIN DE QUE
-----------------------------------------------------------------

((EXTRA MATERIAL FOR INCORPORATING WITH ABOVE MATERIAL))

I don't know=NO LO  SÉ
I don't understand=NO LO ENTIENDO
Please repeat it= POR FAVOR REPITALO
Please speak slowly= POR FAVOR, HABLE DESPACIO
Please write it down=POR FAVOR ESCRIBALO
Please explain it=POR FAVOR, EXPLIQUELO
How do you say (…)=¿CÓMO SE DICE (...)
What is the meaning of (…)= ¿CUÁL ES EL SIGNIFICADO DE (...)
How do you say ( ) in Spanish?=COMO DIRIA  (…….) EN ESPAÑOL?

INCORPORATING DIFFICULTIES WITH KEY WORDS:
DIFICULTADES QUE INCORPORA CON PALABRAS CLAVE:

I don't know, (but) (I'm sure) I will know after you explain it
YO NO SÉ, (PERO) (ESTOY SEGURO) LO SABRÉ DESPUÉS DE QUE LO EXPLIQUE

I don't understand, (but) after you explain it, (perhaps) I will understand
NO LO ENTIENDO, (PERO) DESPUÉS DE EXPLICARLO, (QUIZAS) VOY A ENTENDER

I don't understand (therefore) please write it down (in order) for me to understand
NO LO ENTIENDO (POR LO TANTO), POR FAVOR ANÓTELO (DE MANERA) QUE YO ENTIENDA

I (think) you're speaking (too) fast. Could you speak more slowly (for me?)
YO (CREO) QUE ESTÁ HABLANDO (DEMASIADO) RÁPIDO. ¿PODRÍA HABLAR MÁS DESPACIO 
(PARA MÍ?)
               
﻿Q: How do you write (......)
P: COMO SE ESCRIBRE (…)
A: You can write it like this
R. PUEDES ESCRIBIRLO DE ESTA FORMA
------------------------------------------
Q: How are you learning Spanish? 
P: COMO ESTAS APRENDIENDO ESPAÑOL
A: I’m learning Spanish by using textbooks and practicing with native speakers 
R:ESTOY APRENDIENDO ESPAÑOL UTILIZANDO LIBROS DE TEXTO Y PRACTICANDO CON HABLANTES 
NATIVOS.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Q:Which countries have you been to?
P:EN QUE PAISES HAS ESTADO?
A:I’ve been to Taiwan and Japan
R: HE ESTADO EN TAIWAN Y EN JAPON
------------------------------------------
Q:Which books are you using to learn Spanish?
P:QUE LIBROS ESTAS USANDO PARA 
A:I’m using a textbook called ‘’Teach Yourself’’  
R:ESTOY UTILIZANDO EL LIBRO DE TEXTO LLAMADO “APRENDA USTED MISMO”
--------------------------------------------------------------------                                                                                    APRENDER ESPAÑOL ?
Q:Which city do you live in? 
P:EN QUE CIUDAD VIVE USTED?
A:I live in Columbus, Ohio   
R:YO VIVO EN COLUMBUS, OHIO
-------------------------------
Q:Which language do you enjoy learning the most?   
P:EN QUE IDIOMA TE GUSTA APRENDER MAS? 
A:Actually, I enjoy learning Asian languages the most. 
R:ACTUALMENTE, ME GUSTA mucho MAS APRENDER IDIOMAS ASIATICOS
-----------------------------------------------------------------
((KEYWORDS))

FOR ME PARA MI
MORE MAS
THE XXX... EL...
THE BETTER, EL MEJOR
EASIEST, MAS FACIL
MOST DIFFICULT (SUPERLATIVE),  MAS DIFICIL
TOO (EXCESSIVE), MUY
ALSO, ADEMAS, TAMBIEN
IN COMPARISON TO, EN COMPARACION CON
CERTAINLY,  CIERTAMENTE
IN MY OPINION, EN MI OPINION 
TO ME, A MI
IN MY POINT OF VIEW,  EN MI PUNTO DE VISTA
---------------------------------------------------------------

((EXTRA MATERIAL FOR INCORPORATING WITH ABOVE MATERIAL))

I don't know=NO LO  SÉ
I don't understand=NO LO ENTIENDO
Please repeat it= POR FAVOR REPITALO
Please speak slowly= POR FAVOR, HABLE DESPACIO
Please write it down=POR FAVOR ESCRIBALO
Please explain it=POR FAVOR, EXPLIQUELO
How do you say (…)=¿CÓMO SE DICE (...)
What is the meaning of (…)= ¿CUÁL ES EL SIGNIFICADO DE (...)
How do you say ( ) in Spanish?=COMO DIRIA  (…….) EN ESPAÑOL?

INCORPORATING DIFFICULTIES WITH KEY WORDS:
DIFICULTADES QUE INCORPORA CON PALABRAS CLAVE:

I don't know, (but) (I'm sure) I will know after you explain it
YO NO SÉ, (PERO) (ESTOY SEGURO) LO SABRÉ DESPUÉS DE QUE LO EXPLIQUE

I don't understand, (but) after you explain it, (perhaps) I will understand
NO LO ENTIENDO, (PERO) DESPUÉS DE EXPLICARLO, (QUIZAS) VOY A ENTENDER

I don't understand (therefore) please write it down (in order) for me to understand
NO LO ENTIENDO (POR LO TANTO), POR FAVOR ANÓTELO (DE MANERA) QUE YO ENTIENDA

I (think) you're speaking (too) fast. Could you speak more slowly (for me?)
YO (CREO) QUE ESTÁ HABLANDO (DEMASIADO) RÁPIDO. ¿PODRÍA HABLAR MÁS DESPACIO 
(PARA MÍ?)
               ﻿Q:Which languages are you learning? 
P:QUE IDIOMAS ESTAS APRENDIENDO?
A:Right now, I’m learning Chinese, Japanese and Korean etc. 
R:EN ESTE MOMENTO, ESTOY APRENDIENDO CHINO, JAPONES Y KOREANO
------------------------------------------------------------------
Q: What kind of food do you like? 
P: QUE TIPO DE COMIDA TE GUSTA?
A: I like to eat very spicy food. 
R. ME GUSTA COMER LA COMIDA MUY PICANTE
----------------------------------------
Q: What kind of audio are you using for German? 
P: QUE TIPO DE AUDIO ESTAS UTILIZANDO PARA ALEMAN?
A: I use the audio that comes with Teach Yourself. I also like to use a program 
called ‘’Pimsleur’’ 
R. YO ESTUDIO EL AUDIO QUE VIENE CON “APRENDA USTED MISMO”. TAMBIEN ME GUSTA USAR 
UN PROGRAMA LLAMADO  “PIMSLEUR”
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Q: Have you ever been to Spain? 
P. HAS ESTADO ALGUNA VEZ EN ESPAÑA?
A: I've never been to Spain before, (but) (I'm sure) one day I will get the 
opportunity to go there. 
R. NUNCA HE ESTADO ES ESPAÑA ANTES, PERO ESTOY SEGURO UN DIA VOY A TENER LA 
OPORTUNIDAD DE IR ALLA.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Q: Do you think Spanish is difficult? P: CREES QUE  EL ESPAÑOL ES DIFICIL?
A: Since English is my native tongue, I think Spanish is very difficult. 
However, I must work hard in order to learn it. R. DADO QUE EL INGLES ES MI 
LENGUA MATERNA, YO PIESO QUE EL ESPAÑOL ES MUY DIFICIL. SIN EMBARGO, TENGO QUE 
TRABAJAR DURO PARA PODER APRENDERLO.
----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Q:WHO'S TEACHING YOU THE LANGUAGE
¿QUIÉN TE ENSEÑANZA EL IDIOMA
A: I'm learning the language on my own (now), (but),(although) I'm learning on my
own, I don't (think) it's a difficult task. (As long as) I (continue) to work hard,
I will be successful.
ESTOY APRENDIENDO EL IDIOMA POR MI CUENTA (AHORA), (PERO), (AUNQUE) ESTOY 
APRENDIENDO POR MI PROPIA CUENTA, NO (CREO) QUE SEA UNA TAREA DIFÍCIL.(MIENTRAS) 
YO (CONTINUE) TRABAJANDO DURO, VOY A TENER ÉXITO.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
¿QUÉ IDIOMAS ESTÁS APRENDIENDO?
WHICH LANGUAGES ARE YOU LEARNING?

(AHORA) ESTOY APRENDIENDO ESPAÑOL, ALEMÁN, CHINO (Y) JAPONES, (PERO) YO VOY  
(PROBABLEMENTE) EMPEZAR A APRENDER  (OTROS) IDIOMAS (PORQUE) YO (CREO) QUE EL 
APRENDER (VARIOS) IDIOMAS AL MISMO TIEMPO ES MUY ENRIQUECEDOR. (AUNQUE) ESO 
(PUEDE) SER DIFÍCIL PARA UNA PERSONA, (AL MENOS) EL PROCESO DE APRENDIZAJE SERÁ 
DIVERTIDO.

(Now) I'm learning Spanish, German, Chinese (and) Japanese, (but) I will 
(probably) start learning (other) Languages (because) I (believe) that learning 
(many) languages at the same time is very enriching. (Although) it (may) be 
difficult for an individual, (at least) the learning process will be fun.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
((KEYWORDS))

SOON,  PRONTO
AS A MATTER OF FACT,  COMO DE HECHO
IN FACT, DE HECHO, EN  REALIDAD
HONESTLY, HONESTAMENTE
ACTUALLY，ACTUALMENTE
ALREADY,  YA
HEARD THAT, ESCUCHO QUE
FOR SURE, SIN DUDA
HAD BETTER (I'D BETTER), TENIAN MEJORES (MEJOR QUE ME )
ABOUT, ALREDEDOR
EVEN. INCLUSO
--------------------------------------------------------------------

((EXTRA MATERIAL FOR INCORPORATING WITH ABOVE MATERIAL))

I don't know=NO LO  SÉ
I don't understand=NO LO ENTIENDO
Please repeat it= POR FAVOR REPITALO
Please speak slowly= POR FAVOR, HABLE DESPACIO
Please write it down=POR FAVOR ESCRIBALO
Please explain it=POR FAVOR, EXPLIQUELO
How do you say (…)=¿CÓMO SE DICE (...)
What is the meaning of (…)= ¿CUÁL ES EL SIGNIFICADO DE (...)
How do you say ( ) in Spanish?=COMO DIRIA  (…….) EN ESPAÑOL?

INCORPORATING DIFFICULTIES WITH KEY WORDS:
DIFICULTADES QUE INCORPORA CON PALABRAS CLAVE:

I don't know, (but) (I'm sure) I will know after you explain it
YO NO SÉ, (PERO) (ESTOY SEGURO) LO SABRÉ DESPUÉS DE QUE LO EXPLIQUE

I don't understand, (but) after you explain it, (perhaps) I will understand
NO LO ENTIENDO, (PERO) DESPUÉS DE EXPLICARLO, (QUIZAS) VOY A ENTENDER

I don't understand (therefore) please write it down (in order) for me to understand
NO LO ENTIENDO (POR LO TANTO), POR FAVOR ANÓTELO (DE MANERA) QUE YO ENTIENDA

I (think) you're speaking (too) fast. Could you speak more slowly (for me?)
YO (CREO) QUE ESTÁ HABLANDO (DEMASIADO) RÁPIDO. ¿PODRÍA HABLAR MÁS DESPACIO 
(PARA MÍ?)
               

﻿((1))

Hello, my name is Moses and today I would like to introduce myself in order to 
practice my Spanish. I’m an American and am (now) studying Spanish. I'm living 
in Columbus, Ohio, but I was born in Akron, Ohio. 

HOLA, MI NOMBRE ES MOISÉS Y HOY ME GUSTARÍA PRESENTARME CON EL FIN DE PRACTICAR 
MI ESPAÑOL. SOY NORTEAMERICANO Y ESTOY (AHORA) ESTUDIANDO ESPAÑOL. ESTOY VIVIENDO 
EN COLUMBUS, OHIO, PERO YO NACÍ EN AKRON, OHIO.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
((2))

Akron is north of Columbus and it takes about 2 hours to get there by vehicle. 
I’ve been living in Columbus, Ohio for 8 years (already). I think Columbus is 
great (because) it is a very diverse place. I'm (also) married. (Although) 
I'm married, I haven't any children yet. I’m 28 years old and my wife is 39 years 
old. 

AKRON SE ENCUENTRA AL NORTE DE COLOMBUS Y TOMA ALREDEDOR DE 2 HORAS LLEGAR EN 
VEHÍCULO. HE VIVIDO EN COLUMBUS, OHIO DURANTE 8 AÑOS (YA). CREO QUE COLOMBUS ES 
GRANDIOSO (PORQUE) ES UN LUGAR MUY DIVERSO. SOY (TAMBIÉN) CASADO. (AUNQUE) ESTOY 
CASADO, NO TENGO HIJOS TODAVÍA. TENGO 28 AÑOS Y MI ESPOSA TIENE 39 AÑOS. 
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
((3))

Why am I learning Spanish and (other) languages? I'm learning Spanish and other 
languages (simply) (because) (I think) that learning languages is very enriching
(And) I love meeting people from all over the world. 

¿POR QUÉ ESTOY APRENDIENDO ESPAÑOL Y (OTROS) IDIOMAS? ESTOY APRENDIENDO ESPAÑOL 
Y OTROS IDIOMAS (SIMPLEMENTE) (PORQUE) (CREO) QUE EL APRENDER IDIOMAS ES MUY 
ENRIQUECEDOR (Y) ME ENCANTA CONOCER GENTE DE TODO EL MUNDO. 
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
((4))

(Although) (to many people) learning languages is a difficult task,(but) I think 
it is a fun thing to do and very high rewarding (after) hard work of study. 
I would (honestly) have to say that it is (certainly) worth the effort and time.

(AUNQUE) (PARA MUCHA GENTE) EL APRENDIZAJE DE IDIOMAS ES UNA TAREA DIFÍCIL, 
(PERO) CREO QUE ES UNA COSA DIVERTIDA DE HACER Y MUY ALTAMENTE GRATIFICANTE 
(DESPUÉS) DEL ARDUO TRABAJO DE ESTUDIO. YO PODRIA (SINCERAMENTE) DECIR QUE 
(CIERTAMENTE) VALE LA PENA EL ESFUERZO Y EL TIEMPO.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------
